怦怦、怦怦、怦怦 我斤见了 小驯鹿 我听见了
从我的iPhone发送
我在脸书上屏蔽了玛莎 然后跟酒吧请了一段时间的假
I blocked Martha on Facebook and then took some time off from the pub.
也许是内心抱有一丝侥幸
Maybe in the back of my mind,
只要我长时间不出现 她会因无聊而放弃
I hoped that if I disappeared long enough she might grow bored,
又或者我能淡忘发生的一切
or I might be able to forget what happened.
但在那之后的好几天 我依然能感受到她的触摸
But I still felt her grope for days afterwards.
以及她把我按在墙上时 脖子上的汗臭味
The smell of her neck sweat as she pressed me up against the wall.
我为什么没有反抗?
And why did I freeze?
为什么放任一切发生?
Why did I just let it happen?
这一切感觉如此不真实
It didn't feel human.
从头到尾都像一场噩梦
It never does.
你介段时间都没去酒巴 小驯鹿 出什么事了?
从我的iPhone发送
这么晚还没睡呀
Ooh, you're up late.
嗯 我睡不着
Uh, yeah. I... I couldn't sleep.
周五的约会怎么样?
How was your date Friday?
噢 不太顺利
Oh, not the best.
听着
Look,
希望你不会因为以前跟我女儿交往过
I hope you don't feel like you can't bring people back here
就不好意思带人回来过夜
just because you used to date my daughter.
不 不是那样的 只是...
Oh, no. No, it's, uh... It's not that. It's just, um...
她在回家的路上把我甩了
She ditched me on the way home.
那也太混帐了
What a scumbag.
老实说 唐尼 这样的人 没了她更好
Honestly, Donny, you're better off without someone like that.
我知道不能再窝在家里 无视自身的问题了
I knew I couldn't sit inside anymore ignoring my problems,
所以我前往泰瑞家 决心要做一件
and so I headed round to Teri's, determined to do something
到目前为止最不计后果的事
which felt more reckless than any of my behavior so far.
女王
我要告诉她真相
I was gonna tell her the truth.
你好?
Hello?
您好 请收快递
All right, mate. Delivery.
喔 好的 来了
Oh, okay. Coming.
你搞什么呀 托尼?
What the hell, Tony?
听着 我知道我不是送货员 但我确实有东西要给你
Look, I know I'm not a delivery man, but I am delivering something.
什么?
What?
一句抱歉
An apology.
滚你妈的 俗套的混蛋
Oh, fuck off, you cheesy prick.
这个意思是我可以上去吗?
Does that mean I can come up?
我给你三分钟时间
You have three minutes.
其实我不叫托尼
My name's not Tony.
我就知道 你的真名是什么?
I knew it. What's your real name?
唐尼
It's Donny.
所以你能对跟踪狂说实话 对我却要用假名
Oh, so you can be honest with your stalker but not with me?
你对我说的有一句是真话吗?
I mean, is anything you told me true?
比如你那个超屌的建筑师的工作
Your ballsy fucking building job for one.
假的
No.
为什么?为什么说谎?
Why? Why lie?
不知道 大概是我心虚吧
I don't know. It... it... I just felt vulnerable, I guess.
伪装成另一个人 能让我感觉轻松自在些
It just helped me ease into it, you know, pretending to be someone else.
伪装成一个...怎么说呢
Someone, I don't know,
有男子气概的人
manly.
这真是我听过的最离谱的鬼话
That's, like, the craziest shit I've ever heard.
你他妈的脑子有病 知道吗?
You're fucking sick, you know that?
那么继续吧 你在哪儿工作?
So go on, where do you work?
- 一间酒吧 - 哪间酒吧?
- A pub. - Which pub?
你连这都说不出口
You can't even say that.
卡姆登区的心跳酒吧
The Heart in Camden.
你是干什么的?
What do you do?
我刚才不是告诉你了吗?
I just told you what I did.
没人会甘心在酒吧工作 你的规划是什么?长远打算?
Nobody wants to work at a bar. What's the plan? The big picture?
你希望自己十年后成为怎样的人?
Where do you wanna be in ten years' time?
一名谐星
A comedian.
喔 那很好呀
Oh, that's good.
这件事肯定是个很好的笑料吧
I'm sure this is a right laugh.
是不是? 跟我逢场作戏 好搜集素材?
Is that it? Doing all of this for a bit of material?
什么? 不 泰瑞 我绝不会做那种事
What? No. Teri, I'd never do that.
我不相信你 你说的我一个字都不信
I don't believe you. I don't believe anything you say.
还有
And guess what?
三分钟时间到了 混蛋 滚出我的家
Time's up, dickhead. Get the fuck out my house.
你听我说
Listen.
编辑资料
托尼
唐尼
建筑师
谐星
“谐星”
唐尼
Donny! Donny!
过来 和烹饪小组的大伙儿打个招呼
Come here. Come say hello to the cooking group.
他来了
There he is!
你们有正经做过料理吗?
Have you guys done any cooking whatsoever?
- 我们还在研究酒焰灼烧法 - 对
- We're still on the flambé.
这周有什么收获? 有新人加入吗?
Who've you got? Any new recruits?
对了 有的 这是宝儿
Oh, yes. This is Beau.
- 宝儿是职业油漆工 - 你好 宝儿
- Beau is a painter by trade. - Hello, Beau.
还有希拉 但是天啊 抱歉 我忘记你是做什么的了
And this is Sheila. But, oh God, sorry, I've forgotten what it is you do.
我是律师
I'm a lawyer.
驯鹿宝贝 如果你不相我去你家
未什么还总走运河那条路回去?
从我的iPhone发送
驯鹿宝贝》
初到伦敦时
When I first came to London,
我和当时的女朋友琪莉一起
I moved with my then girlfriend, Keeley,
搬进了她妈妈的家 一边借住一边找房子
into her mother's home while we tried to find a place to build a life together.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
但原本计划的两周延长到了六个月
But an intended stopgap of two weeks turned into six months,
再又到一年
turned into one year,
直到她骂我性冷淡 然后搬了出去
turned into her calling me an emotionless prick and moving out
我都没能成功勃起过一次
before I could manage an erection.
在那之后 令人啼笑皆非又难以置信的是
So then, in an irony I couldn't quite believe,
我俨然跟他的母亲过成了两口子
I found myself married to her mother.
琪莉搬出去之后不久
Shortly after Keeley moved out,
丽兹的大儿子不幸死于一场登山事故
Liz's eldest son died in an abseiling accident,
刚面临新的生活状况 就遇上这样的神展开 简直太硬核了
which was about as intense a way into a new living situation as could be.
天啊 真抱歉
Oh my God, I'm... I am so sorry.
不 没关系
No, no, it's fine.
- 你确定吗? 我可以... - 没事
- Are you sure? I mean, I...- Yeah.
好的 好吧 我冲杯咖啡就走
Okay. Um... All right. I... I'll be very quick.
我从这边绕过去
I'll go round this way.
你还好吗? 看见你真好
You all right? Good to see you.
三分钟就好
For three minutes.
有时我确实会怀疑 是不是因为恰好在那时痛失爱子
And I do sometimes question whether the timing of Liz's son's passing
使得丽兹把我当成了儿子的替身
lead her to see me as an extension of him.
仿佛他出了一趟远门 回来时变得有点更像苏格兰人
Like he left the house one day and came back a little more Scottish,
多了些神经质 但恕我直言
a little more neurotic, and, dare I say,
山地绳降的技术也变强了
a little better at abseiling.
这个给你穿吧 在阁楼找到的
I got this. Found it in the loft.
- 不 我不能穿 - 他品位可好了
- Oh, no, I couldn't. - He dressed well.
确实 但我真的不能穿 感觉不太合适
He did. But, honestly, I couldn't. It wouldn't feel right.
你先拿着吧 好好考虑一下
Why don't I leave this with you? Think it through.
丽兹 我真的不能收下这件外套
Honestly, Liz, I absolutely cannot accept this coat.
多么离奇的生活状况呀
It was a strange living situation,
跟我前女友那位离过两次婚 且刚经历丧子之痛的母亲捆绑在一起
to be shacked up with the twice-divorced, grieving mother of my ex-girlfriend.
但最终 我渐渐开始庆幸有她的陪伴
But in the end, I really grew to value her presence in my life.
她的乐观和积极正好能给
She had the kind of boundless positivity
在难以言说的困境中挣扎的人 传递无穷的正能量
reserved only for those fighting the most unspeakable circumstances.
所以当琪莉发现我打算留下时
Therefore, when Keeley found out about my plans to stay,
她同意了 但有一个条件
she let me, on one condition.
我绝不能把麻烦惹上门
That I never bring chaos to her mother's door.
老实说 我真不明白你是怎么做到的
I don't know how you do it. Honestly, I don't.
做到什么 姐妹?
Do what, hen?
这么晚不睡 居然连口酒都不喝
Stay up this late without so much as a tipple.
我还是不喝酒的好 平常就已经够疯狂了
I'm better without it. Crazy enough as it is, me.
我老爸以前常说
My old man used to say
哪怕滴酒不沾 我也整天像个醉鬼一样
I'm a full-time drunk without touching a drop.
我懂你
I know that feeling.
她真不错 我喜欢她
She's good. I like her.
- 我给你把酒满上? - 今天该告一段落了吧
- Top-up? - I think we should maybe wrap up.
请给我一杯健怡可乐 谢谢
A Diet Coke, please.
喝那么多咖啡因 你会兴奋得整晚睡不着觉吧
You'll be bouncing off the walls with all that caffeine.
我倒想呢
Hopefully.
但要兴奋起来 我可能需要一点帮助 好吧?
Might need a bit of help bouncing, mind.
丽兹 我觉得今晚就到此为止吧
Listen, uh, Liz, I think maybe we should call it.
我今天起太早了 需要好好睡一觉
I'm... I'm up early, and I need... I need a decent night's sleep.
我可以留下陪你
I could stay here.
欢迎之至
You'd be so welcome.
这里以前是出租房 有很多空房间
This is an old lodging house. Plenty of rooms to spare.
我觉得最好还是别让玛莎留宿吧
I actually think it's best if Martha doesn't stay tonight.
她叫希拉 天哪
Her name's Sheila! Oh my God!
你怎么就醉了?
You're supposed to be the sober one.
希拉 我想你一定会保持安静 不吵着这位唐尼小哥睡觉的吧
Sheila, I assume I can trust you to stay quiet for young Donny here.
当然 就算想闹出动静 我也会忍住的
Oh, absolutely. I'll bite my lip if I think of making any noise.
好极了 那就这么定了 我去帮你铺床
Great. That's settled, then. I'll pad you out a bed.
唐尼 你给希拉泡杯茶助眠吧?
Donny, why don't you make Sheila a nice cup of tea for beddies?
你现在马上给我离开这里
You're to leave here, right now.
不 我要留下过夜
No. I'm staying the night.
否则就太失礼了 我的朋友丽兹正帮我铺床呢
It'd be rude not to. My new friend Liz is fastening me up a bed.
她不是你的朋友 你也不能留下
She's not your friend, and you're not fucking staying.
别对我这么凶
Don't get stuffy with me.
你该庆幸
You're lucky I'm still interested
我被你在脸书上屏蔽了还肯来找你
after you pissed off from the pub and blocked me on Facebook.
我现在不想说这个 你要是再这么乱来
I'm not talking about this. If you continue this bullshit any longer,
我就报警了
I'll call the police.
你敢 我是律师
You wouldn't dare. I'm a lawyer.
干我这行是有行事规范的
I've got certain standards to live up to.
我可不想警察跑来无事生非
I don't want the police making waffles out of nothing.
那就快走 以后也别来这个烹饪课
Then leave. Stay away from this cooking class.
别接近丽兹 别靠近这所房子
Stay away from Liz, and stay away from this house.
清楚了吗?
Is that clear?
好的 那好
Okay. All right.
说吧 你想怎么...
What's it gonna--
别报警 我莱时碰巧她们在聚会
旦我对亨饪没兴趣 所以去它的巴 我点外卖就好
从我的iPhone发送
我担惊受怕了一整晚
I spent all night panicking,
玛莎知道了我的住处 会做出什么事来?
thinking of the things Martha could do now she knew where I lived.
她可能会成天过来打转
She could come over all the time,
在走廊里缠着我
hound me in the corridors of my home,
大半夜溜上我的床
sneak into my bed in the dead of the night.
到时候会怎样?
And what would happen then?
我真该当机立断去找警察 可我却决定先找她谈谈
I should have gone to the police, but I decided to speak to her first,
警告她 再敢出现在我家
tell her that if she ever came to the house again,
就让她后悔莫及
there would be absolutely no going back.
但她一直没有出现
But she never showed.
她知道那是我返工后第一次上班
She knew it was my first shift back.
这样就让她从我的生活中消失了吗?
Was that all it took to remove her from my life?
就凭那天威胁她说要报警?
One threat about calling the police?
一切都感觉太简单、太轻松
It all just seemed too simple, too easy,
太...
too...
见鬼
Oh shit!
可恶
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
我去开门
I'll get this.
我告诉过你不要来这里
I told you not to come here.
我觉得你对此没有发言权吧
I don't think you have any say in the matter.
琪莉
Keeley.
你怎么...
What are you...
- 你怎么来了? - 怎么 我不能回我妈妈家吗?
- What are you doing here? - What, at my family home?
- 我不知道你要来 - 是我让妈妈别告诉你的
- I didn't know you had plans to be down. - I told my mum not to tell you.
我不想小题大做
I didn't wanna make a big deal out of it.
但看你这副表情 大概是事与愿违了
But judging by your facial expressions, probably too late for that.
不 我只是...你打算待多久?
No, no, I just, um... I just, uh... How long are you staying for?
- 想待多久就待多久 - 是啊 不 当然
- As long as I bloody like. - Yeah, yeah. No, of course.
对 这是一个很严肃的问题 你女朋友是个神经病
Yeah, well, this is serious. Your girlfriend is a psycho.
她不停在脸书上联系我 缠着我不放
She keeps contacting me on Facebook. She will not leave me alone.
我都开始担心她会来找我了
I'm starting to worry I'm gonna bump into her somewhere.
你能跟她谈谈吗?
Can you talk to her?
- 她不是我女朋友 - 那她是谁?
- She's not my girlfriend. - Who is she, then?
你得把这事解决了
You need to sort this out.
为什么是我? 这事跟我没关系
Why me? I don't have anything to do with this.
胡说 肯定是你做了什么 才惹上这麻烦的
Bullshit. You would have done something to bring this on.
又来了 什么都怪在我头上
Here we go. Blame me like you always do.
对 就是怪你 你就爱没事找事
Yeah, I do blame you. You love drama.
只要能摆脱一潭死水的生活 你什么都干得出来
Anything to take you away from the stasis that is your own life.
哇 不错嘛 你上了那么久的心理学研究生课程
Wow, wow. It's great to see you putting that psychology postgrad to good use
可算是学以致用了
after all this time.
我还以为你在花店工作 是在浪费才华呢
There was me thinking you were wasting it working in a flower shop.
她再这么骚扰我的话 我就要告诉我妈了
If she keeps pestering me, I'm gonna tell my mum.
那你立马就会被扫地出门 没有便宜房租蹭了
And then you'll be out of here before you can say mates' rates.
好讨厌琪莉那臭婊子 真是的 我到哪逗能见到她
从我的iPhone发送
现在玛莎每天都守在外面
Every day now, Martha would be outside.
这颗定时炸弹不知何时会要了我的命
This ticking time bomb on my life.
哪怕我一大早出门 她也已经守在那里了
I would leave first thing in the morning, and she would be there.
我爱你 小奶头 上班时要想我哦
I love you, nipple. Think of me at work today.
有时我会忙到深夜十一二点才回家
Then I would come back, sometimes as late as 11 or 12 at night,
而她依然守在那里
and she would still be there.
工作顺利吗 小驯鹿? 有没有想我?
How was your shift, reindeer? Did you think of me?
真想不通这对她有什么好处 她再没靠近过我
I never understood what she got from it. She never approached me.
也再没有进过这栋房子
She never came to the house again.
每次丽兹路过 她都会避开
She avoided Liz whenever she passed.
她每天等待十五六个小时
It was all catcalls and snatched glimpses,
只为一场转瞬而逝的相遇 远远地喊上几句话 看上我几眼
as she devoted 15, 16-hour days to a fleeting encounter.
讲个笑话吧 笑笑骨 让我乐一乐
Tell us a joke, funny bones. Make me smile.
但很快 随着时间的流逝 气温逐渐下降
But soon, as time wore on and the temperature dropped,
我注意到了玛莎的一个变化
I noticed a change in Martha
她开始就这么怔怔地注视着虚空
as she descended into this staring.
玛莎
Martha.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
然后那害我落到
It all just came back
如此田地的同情心 又回来了
to those same feelings of empathy which got me here.
天哪 玛莎 你在这外面坐了多久了?
Jesus Christ, Martha, how long have you been sitting out here for?
我这里有纸巾
Here. I've got a tissue somewhere.
给
There.
好吧
All right.
我来帮你...
Here, let me, um...
你整晚这么坐下去会冻死的
You're gonna catch your death if you sit out here all night.
我送你回家 好吗?
I'm gonna take you back to yours, okay?
我的房东有车 我可以...
My landlady has a car, and I'll...
开车送你回去
I'll drive you.
好了 起来吧
All right, come on.
来 我们走
Here. Let's go.
好了 去坐会儿吧
Here. Sit down.
我给你泡杯茶
Gonna make you a cup of tea.
你得尽快让身子暖和起来
It's important you heat up as soon as possible.
梦中情人
玛莎·史考特 法学学士一等学位
给 小心烫
Here. It's hot.
玛莎 你不能再守在 我家对面的那个公交车站了
Martha, you have to stop hanging around that bus stop on my road.
为什么?
Why?
因为你之所以那么做 只是因为我家离那里不到30米
Because you're only there because my house is 30 yards away.
你住在我朋友隔壁
You live next door to my friend.
那你为什么会待在车站 而不是你朋友家里?
Then why are you there and not next door at your friend's?
玛莎 求你了 别这样
Martha, please, don't do this.
现在的住所对我来说很重要 我住不起其他地方
My home means a great deal to me, and I can't afford to be anywhere else.
见鬼
Fuck.
哎呀 你怎么哭了 小奶头?
Oh no. Why are you crying, nipple?
不 我没哭 我只是...
No, I'm not fucking crying. I just...
出什么事了? 告诉我
What's wrong? Tell me.
是你 玛莎 问题就出在你
You, Martha. You're what's wrong.
那我怎样才能帮上你呢 小驯鹿? 你需要什么?
What can I do to help though, reindeer? What... what do you need?
空间
Space.
你想远离我?
Fr... from me?
你想分手吗?
From us?
你在胡说什么啊? 我们根本没在一起过 真他妈见鬼
Oh, what are you talking about? There is no us! Fucking hell.
无论我跟你说什么
I can say anything to you, can't I,
你都只会选择性地听自己想听的话
and you'll just pick and choose the bits you want to hear.
瞧你这副样子
I mean, look at you,
这么看着我 就好像...
staring at me like...
好像什么?
Like what?
我是说...
I mean...
你真的认为我们在交往 是吗?
you believe it, don't you?
玛莎
Martha.
我要跟你分手
I'm breaking up with you.
不
Oh no.
不要啊
不要 求你了 别跟我分手
Oh no, please. No, don't.
不要分手
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
求你了
Please.
- 我不会再去那里了 - 不 别这样好吗?玛莎
- I'll stop, I'll stop. - No, don't do that, Martha, okay?
听我说 好吗? 你听我说
- Don't. Just listen to me, okay? Listen. - Oh no.
别把这当成一种失去 把它视为收获吧
Don't think of this as something you lost. Think of it as something you gained.
如果你现在放手
If you stop now
再也别联系我
and never contact me again,
还能留下美好的回忆 不是吗?
it's almost been perfect, hasn't it?
一段耐人寻味的 童话般的回忆
This fairy tale to look back on.
但要不想让童话破灭
But for it to remain a fairy tale,
你现在就得注重分手后的界限
you now need to respect the boundaries of the breakup.
你不想破坏童话的结局 对吧?
You wouldn't wanna spoil that fairy-tale ending, would you?
不想
No.
我不会的 弗兰基
I wouldn't, Frankie.
我不会破坏我们曾经拥有的一切
I won't do nothing to harm what we had.
失落、空嘘... 我知道你也系认真的 你的眼神...
看来介次要真的说再见了
我爱你 小驯鹿 泥永远在我心里
从我的iPhone发送
好的 各位 听好了
Okay, guys. All right, listen up.
欢迎进入半决赛 你们每人有五分钟的表演时间
Welcome to the semifinals. You each have five minutes.
红灯会在计时结束前15秒开始闪烁
The red light will flash 15 seconds before the end,
谁超过了指定的时间 就会被取消资格
and if you go over your allotted time, you will be disqualified.
- 这位是主持人格兰达 - 大家好
- Now, Glenda here is your compère. - Sup, guys?
你们有任何要求 或者不明白的地方 都可以找她
So any requests, specific introductions, she's your man.
好了 祝各位好运
Right. Good luck, everyone.
我在心里将这场演出当作了 我所有问题的答案
I had built this gig up in my head as the answer to all my problems.
只要晋级决赛
Getting to the final might be enough
或许我就能走出过去几年的阴影
to drag me out of the hell of the past few years.
没有了玛莎的纠缠 我真的感觉前路已经畅通无阻了
And with Martha gone, it really felt like there was nothing in my way.
直到...
That was until...
泰瑞
Teri.
- 搞什么呀? - 不客气
- What the hell? - Warm welcome.
不 只是...
No, no, it's just...
我已经好几周没见到你了
I haven't seen you for weeks.
- 你来这里做什么? - 来观看演出
- What are you doing here? - Coming to see the show.
- 你开玩笑的吧? - 不能更认真了
- You can't be serious. Deadly.
我想做个彻底的了结
If anything's gonna give me closure,
看你在好几百人面前一败涂地 这方法再合适不过了
it's seeing you fail spectacularly in front of hundreds of people.
20个人够吗?
Will 20 do?
抱歉 这些是?
And, sorry, these are?
我的朋友
Oh. My friends.
他们来防止我再次因为某个渣男
They're here to stop me sliding into a familiar pattern
而做出各种丢脸的事情
of shame-based behavior with horrible men.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
好吧 要说我先前没觉得紧张 现在我真的紧张起来了
Well, if I wasn't nervous before, I am now.
很好 我们可是很难取悦的哦
Good. We're very hard to please.
快来 哥们 我要开门了
Come on, bro. I need to open the doors.
好的 抱歉 我马上过去 好吗? 很快就好
Yeah, sorry. I'll... I'll be right up, okay? I'll be two seconds, yeah?
抱歉 我也不知为何刚才说要留下 我得上去了 祝你们愉快
Sorry, I don't know why I opted to stay. I'm gonna go too. Enjoy the show.
所以爸爸 如果你在看演出...
So, Dad, if you're watching this...
- 天哪 真要命 天啊 - ...穿条裤子吧
- Oh, Jesus. Oh, fucking hell. Jesus. - ...put on some trousers.
待会儿要我介绍一下你吗?
You want an introduction?
要的 你能说我有点疯癫吗?
Oh yeah. Yeah, yeah. Can you introduce me as a little bit mad?
给观众一点心理准备 因为我的演出有些与众不同
It might help set up the audience for something a little bit different.
当然 下一个就到你了 祝你好运 伙计
Sure. You're on next. Good luck, mate.
好的 谢谢
- 好样的 很棒的表演 - 怎么样 精彩吗 女士们先生们?
- Well done. That was great. How good was that?
好的 接下来这位艺人真是个疯子
Okay. Now, your next act is mental.
他一直在后台跟踪骚扰我们 大伙儿都吓得够呛
He's been stalking about backstage, freaking us all out.
这也太夸张了
That's too much.
所以 大伙儿最好看紧自己的女儿...
So you're gonna have to lock up your daughters.
她把我说成个变态了
Makes me sound like a pervert.
- ...让我们欢迎他上台... - 见鬼
Please welcome to the stage... - Fuck's sake!
- ...唐尼·邓恩  - 好吧 来了
...Donny Dunn! - All right, yeah.
对 那个...
Yeah, that's...
对 抱歉 不用看那么紧的
Uh, yeah, sorry. Uh, leave those doors unlocked.
这不是玩笑
That's... Yep, that's not a joke.
就是那个...我不会跟踪你们的女儿 这话说得我像是个...
It's just... I'm not after your daughters. That makes me sound like a... a...
我不是变态
I'm not a pervert.
其实我觉得这句话很奇怪 "看紧你们的女儿"
I've always found that phrase weird. "Lock up your daughters."
难道要把全城的女人关起来 而不去解决那个变态吗?
Like they lock up all the women in town, instead of dealing with the one pervert.
结果不是适得其反吗?
Talk about counterproductive.
好吧 我假设那是个变态 他也有可能
I... I assume he's a pervert anyway. I mean, he could be, like, a... like a...
是个连环杀人犯 或者对年轻姑娘
serial killer or something, you know, with a
有特殊嗜好的
particular penchant for, uh,
禽兽
young girls.
所以 对 我不会跟踪你们的女儿 只是想事先声明这点
So, yeah, not after your daughters. Uh, just wanna make that clear up top.
我来自苏格兰 所以我渴望的是你们的糕点
I'm from Scotland originally, so it's your pastries I'm after.
我知道我听起来不像苏格兰人
I know I don't sound Scottish,
但作为证据 瞧我这副德行吧
but if you need proof, just look at the state of me.
我才刚满16岁哦
I've just turned 16.
好的 很好 对 好了 我要开始搞笑了
All right, good. Yeah. All right, let's do some jokes.
唐尼·邓恩
Donny Dunn.
三个礼拜前 我女朋友来找我
So three weeks ago, my girlfriend came up to me,
她说想试试跟我玩双修
and she says she really wants to try tantric sex,
就是那种延迟性高潮的房中术
the art of delaying an orgasm.
我回答说:"嘿 我跟你交往了五年
So I replied, "Hey, I've been going out with you for five years,
你一次高潮都没到过
and you haven't come once."
还想要我怎样?"
"What more do you want from me?"
唐尼·邓恩
Donny Dunn.
两周前 我女朋友来找我说
Two weeks ago, my girlfriend came up to me and said,
"我觉得我们俩不合适"
"I just think we're not working as lovers."
我回答道:"噢 拜托
To which I replied, "Oh, come on."
之前你不想做我表妹了 也是这么说的"
"That's what you said about the cousins thing."
唐尼·邓恩
Donny Dunn.
那之后又过了一周 她来找我说
Then one week after that, she came up to me and she said,
"我想离开你"
"I'm thinking of leaving you."
我的回答是
To which I replied,
"求你了 不要"
"Please. No."
唐尼·邓恩
Donny Dunn.
好吧 对了 我们来上道具吧 好的
All right, um, yeah. Let's do some... Let's do some prop stuff. All right.
♪ 钟情于你 ♪
♪ Especially for you ♪
♪ 多想你知道 我饱受煎熬 ♪
♪ I wanna let you know What I was going through ♪
♪ 分开的日子里 不停思念你 ♪
♪ All the time we were apart I thought of you ♪
谢谢 那我继续了
Thanks for that. Moving on.
我好想你
I miss you.
我也想你 陌生的女士
Um, I miss you too, random stranger.
我才不是什么陌生人 我是你的前女友
I'm not a random stranger. I'm your ex.
别这么无情呀
Don't be so cruel.
你刚才说的前女友是谁?
Who's that girl you were talking about?
是你脸书上那个琪莉吗?
Is that Keeley from your Facebook?
不 那是我虚构出来的人物 有一种东西叫小说 知道吗?
No, it's a little thing called fiction, actually.
你看《权力的游戏》时
Just so you know, when you watch Game of Thrones,
知道里面那些不是真的龙吧?
those aren't real dragons, you do realize that?
真搞不懂他们为什么都在笑 你讲的笑话烂透了
I don't know why they're all laughing. You're absolutely shite.
女士们先生们 我来给你们介绍一下好了
Okay, just to give you some context, ladies and gentlemen,
她叫...
this is, uh...
她叫玛莎 是个跟踪狂 最近盯上我了 跟玛莎打个招呼吧
This is Martha, my stalker. Say hello to Martha.
你胆敢这么说我
Don't you dare say that to me!
我可是付了钱来看演出的客人 你竟敢暗骂我动机不纯
I'm a paying customer. How dare you insinuate mixed intentions!
立刻向我道歉
You apologize to me right now.
见鬼 谁把精神病院的门给打开了?
Fucking hell. Who unlocked the doors to Broadmoor?
你不能说我是跟踪狂
You can't call me a stalker.
你才是大晚上在我家外面 鬼鬼祟祟转悠的人
You're the one creeping round my house at night.
透过我的窗户往里偷看
Peering in through my windows.
给我发电子邮件 求我让你插我的小菊花
Sending me emails begging for my bumhole.
我真的不知道她在说什么
I... I... I genuinely have no idea what she's talking about.
你知道
Yes, you do.
我可以给他们看
I'll show them.
- 他知道我在说什么 - 我们能请她出去吗?
- He does know what I'm talking about. - Can we get her out?
- 看 这里 - 谁来帮帮忙?
- Someone? - Look. There.
我不知道那是什么东西
I don't know what that is.
抱歉 麻烦把她赶出去好吗? 行吗?
Look, sorry, can we get her out, please? Yep?
看 一封邮件 上面写着肛交
Look, an email. Anal sex, it says.
这里 看见了吗? 看 肛交
There, see? Look. Anal.
- 来吧 亲爱的 我带你出去 - 这上面写的肛交
Come on, darling. Out we go. Anal sex, it says.
- 别用你的手碰我 - 我们走
- Don't you put your hands on me. Out we go.
无论如何你们都没有权利碰我
You're not allowed to put your hands on me. Under no circumstances.
不 他是个喜欢肛交的变态
No. He's a bumhole lover, this one.
一个下流的肛交癖
A proper dirty little bumhole lover.
一文不值的酒吧小侍应 喜欢肛交的混蛋猥琐男
A filthy little two-bit, barman, bumhole bastard!
别碰我
Don't touch me!
真是去哪都不能带上我妈呀
Can't take my mum anywhere.
见鬼
Fuck!
泰瑞 见鬼
Teri. Oh fuck.
快进来
Get in. Get in, quick. Quick.
- 那就是玛莎吗? - 对
- Was that Martha? - Yeah.
- 她真是疯了 - 我知道 我们快走吧
- That was nuts. - I know. We need to get out of here.
我想见见她
- I wanna meet her.
- 你在开玩笑吧? - 没开玩笑 我想见她
- You're not serious? - I am. I wanna meet her.
不 泰瑞 我劝你还是算了吧
No, Teri. That is not a good idea.
你想想看 我是一名治疗师 我可以开导她
It is. Think about it. I'm a therapist. I can get through to her.
你想想看吧 她是个疯子 那种人是没法沟通的
Think about it. She's insane. There's no getting through to her.
你跟我一起从后面下去
You'll have to come down the back way with me.
就当是为了我 好吗?
Just do this for me, yeah?
好吧 胆小鬼
Fine. Loser.
感觉有点滑稽 你居然害怕一个中年女人
It's kinda comical, you being scared of a middle-aged woman.
先别忙着笑 我也很怕大楼后方废弃的大房间
Wait until you hear about my phobia of massive, abandoned fucking back rooms.
- 小驯鹿? - 见鬼
- Reindeer? - Oh shit!
该死
Shit.
Shit!
你岗才是跟别人在一起吗?
iPhone发送
- 天哪 - 真他妈见鬼
- Oh my God. - Fucking hell.
我整个人都在发抖
I'm, like, shaking.
天啊 她好可怕
Jesus. She's terrifying.
你觉得她看到我们了吗?
Do you think she saw us?
- 希望没有 - 真要命
- I hope not. - Fucking hell.
要去喝一杯吗?
Shall we, uh... Shall we get a drink, maybe?
我不知道
I don't know.
我其实没打算跟你来这里的
I didn't really plan on being here with you.
再给我一次机会吧 求你了
Look, just give me one more chance, please.
问题不是我想不想给你机会 而是...
Look, it's not about me giving you another chance. It's just...
我真的不想被人看见 我跟演出上那个蹩脚谐星在一起
I don't really wanna be seen with the shit comedian from the show.
你可以坐在我后面那桌
You can always sit on the table behind me
背对着我说话
and talk to me over your shoulder if you'd like.
是啊 你就喜欢玩那套 对吧?
Yeah, you'd love that, wouldn't you?
天哪 刚才的演出简直是灾难
Oh, Jesus, that gig was brutal.
是啊 但其实原本还挺顺利的
Yeah. It was going so well too.
要不是中途被她打断 我真心觉得你有机会晋级的
I really would have fancied your chances, had she not interrupted.
- 你真会说话 - 那当然
- You always know the right thing to say. - Mm-hmm.
你为什么会留下来找我?
So, what made you stick around?
看见你在台上饱受煎熬
Seeing you struggle up top.
我真想冲上去给你一个拥抱
I just wanted to come on stage, give you a hug,
告诉你找一份真正的工作
and tell you to get a real job.
而且我看见你修改了 网站上的个人信息 还有...
Also, I saw you changed your profile on the website, and...
我也不知道
I don't know.
我想着这也许值得让我再考虑一下
I thought that was maybe worth something.
你觉得 你能对我做过的事既往不咎吗?
Do you ever think that you'd be able to see past what I did?
不 大概不能
Mm, no. Probably not.
从现在起
It'll be the baseline
它会奠定我们每一次争吵的基调
for every single argument we have from now on.
大致上说就是 从今往后 永远都是我赢
I win, essentially, for the rest of time.
好啊 这我应该能接受
Yeah, I think I can live with that.
这个臭婊子是谁?
Who's the skank?
你一定就是玛莎了
You must be Martha.
他跟我说了很多关于你的事
I've heard so much about you.
- 我从来没听他提起过你 - 好吧 冷静点 玛莎
- I've heard fuck all about you. - All right. Calm down, Martha.
这该死的臭婊子是谁?
Who's the fucking skank?
泰瑞莎 她叫泰瑞莎
Teresa. Her name is Teresa.
唐尼 我想玛莎还需要更多信息
Donny, I think Martha's gonna need a little bit more information than that.
我知道你为什么这么做 但现在不是好时机
Teri, I get why you're doing this, but now is not the right time.
坐下 现在时机刚刚好
Sit down. It's exactly the right time.
- 别碰他 贱人 - 玛莎
- Don't you touch him, bitch! - Martha.
我对天发誓 你再碰他一下
I swear to God, you lay another finger on him,
我就撕了你的嘴 我说到做到
I'm gonna wipe that lip from you, mark my words.
说真的 我们出去吧 玛莎
Seriously. Let's step outside, Martha, okay?
老实说 唐尼 我本该问你有没有上过她
Honestly, Donny, I'd ask if you're fucking,
但我不认为你会把鸡鸡 塞进那么肮脏的地方
but I don't think you'd stoop so low as to put your dick somewhere this dirty.
- 你说"肮脏"是什么意思? - 你懂我的意思
- What do you mean, "dirty"? - You know what I mean.
好吧 我们大家都冷静一点 好吗?
Okay, I think we should all calm down a bit, yeah?
不好 除非你先告诉我
No, not until you tell me
这个高颧骨的外来骚货是谁
who the foreign tart with the high cheekbones is,
瞧她一脸 "你没有权利在这里叫嚣"的样子
acting like I've got no right to be here,
但这是我的国家 她才是无权出现在这里的人
when she's got no right to be in my fucking country!
好了 玛莎 请你冷静点
All right, Martha. Calm down.
- 你们没事吧? - 没事 我来处理
Everything all right? - I've got this.
你成天就爱跟这种人鬼混吗? 瘾君子 强奸犯 这种外来人
Is this the company you're keeping? Druggies and rapists, the lot of 'em.
我对天发誓 要是可以的话
I swear to God, if I had my way,
我肯定立马 把他们用来偷渡的小船打沉
I'd sink their boats on the horizon.
这个疯子的胡言乱语我已经听够了
You know what? I'm getting bored of this now.
所以唐尼 跟她直说了吧 你在跟我约会
So, Donny, why don't you just tell her that you're on a date with me
请她滚开
and she needs to fuck off?!
婊子
Whore.
臭婊子
Whore!
该死的婊子
Fucking whore!
你这肮脏的小婊子
You're a nasty, nasty little whore!
- 玛莎 别闹了 - 死贱人
Martha, come on! - Fucking skank!
- 该死的丑八怪  - 玛莎
- You fucking ugly bitch! - Martha!
放开她 玛莎
Let go, Martha!
靴子
Boots!
住手 玛莎 冷静
Stop, Martha! Calm down!
- 小贱人 靴子  - 谁他妈的快来帮忙
- Little bitch! The boots! - Someone fucking help!
她的靴子
The boots!
靴子 贱人 婊子
- Look at the boots! Bitch! Whore! Martha, get up!
你看起来像个男人
You look like a man!
好了 快给我滚出去 玛莎
Right, get the fuck out of here, Martha!
穿靴子的臭婊子
The fucking boots bitch!
你他妈的就是个疯子
You're fucking insane!
- 才不是呢 - 闭嘴 听我说
- That isn't true! - Shut your fucking mouth and listen to me!
这世上就算有平行世界 也不会有任何一个我想要你 懂吗?
There isn't a fucking parallel world where I would want you, okay?
离我远一点 听见没?
So you stay away from me, do you hear?
哪怕你只是朝我的方向闻一下
If you so much as fucking sniff in my fucking direction,
我都会宰了你
I will see to your grave.
明白了吗?
Do you understand?
你他妈的明白了吗?
Do you fucking understand?!
明白了
I understand.
快他妈滚出我的生活
Now get the fuck out of my life.
麻烦让一让
Out of the fucking way, please.
根据理查德·加德的话剧 《驯鹿宝贝》改编